Guide to the Oregonian photographs collection circa 1850-1984
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Portland, 1884-1983; Series C
  - Consolidated Metco, Inc. (Box-folder 48/21)
  - Consular Corps (Box-folder 48/22)
  - Contact Center (Box-folder 48/23)
  - Contremporary Crafts Gallery (Box-folder 48/24)
  - Continental Can Co. (Box-folder 48/25)
  - Continental Grain Co. (Box-folder 48/26)
    Contains photographs of building's demolition in August 1968.
  - Cook Industries, Inc. (Box-folder 48/27)
  - Copeland Lumber Yard (Box-folder 48/28)
  - Copper Castle (Box-folder 48/29)
  - Copperfield Jail (Box-folder 48/30)
  - Corbett Building (Box-folder 48/31)
  - Corbett Home (Box-folder 48/32)
    Residence of Henry Corbett.
  - Cordray Theater (Box-folder 48/33)
  - Corning Glass Factory (Box-folder 48/34)
  - Cosmopolitan Club (Box-folder 48/35)
  - Couch Park (Box-folder 48/36)
  - Council Crest Park (Box-folder 48/37)
  - Crawford Home (Box-folder 49/1)
  - Crematoriums (Box-folder 49/2)
  - Creston Park (Box-folder 49/3)
  - Croatian Day Picnic (Box-folder 49/4)
  - Croatian Fraternal Union (Box-folder 49/5)
  - Crown Plaza (Box-folder 49/6)
  - Crystal Springs Rhododendron Garden (Box-folder 49/7)
  - Cub Scouts (Box-folder 49/8)
  - Curtis Publishing Co. (Box-folder 49/9)
  - D. H. Overmyer Warehouse Co. (Box-folder 49/10)
  - Dad's Root Beer Bottling Co. (Box-folder 49/11)
  - Daughters of Neptune (Box-folder 49/12)
  - Daughters of the Nile (Box-folder 49/13)
  - Daughters of Penelope (Box-folder 49/14)
  - Daughters of Union Veterans of the Civil War (Box-folder 49/15)
  - David Campbell Memorial Fountain (Box-folder 49/16)
    Includes photographs of commemorative services for fallen firemen held at the fountain.
  - Davidson Baking Co. (Box-folder 49/17)
  - De Luxe Cab Co. (Box-folder 49/18)
  - Dekum Building (Box-folder 49/19)
  - Dekum Court (Box-folder 49/20)
  - DeMolay (Box-folder 49/21)
    Includes photographs DeMolay Honorees and DeMolay Day.
  - Del Mar of Northwest, Inc. (Box-folder 49/22)
  - Delphian Society (Box-folder 49/23)
  - Delta Delta Delta (Box-folder 49/24)
  - Delta Gamma (Box-folder 49/25)
  - Delta Gamma Kappa (Box-folder 49/26)
  - Delta Park (Box-folder 49/27)
    Includes images of stadiums planned for the park.
    See also: Oregon - Vanport.
  - Delta Sigma Theta (Box-folder 49/28)
  - Delta Theta Phi Convention, 1947 July (Box-folder 49/29)
  - Delta Zeta (Box-folder 49/30)
  - Demonstrations (Box-folder 49/31)
  - Demonstrations - American Legion Convention, 1970 August-September (Box-folder 49/32)
    See also: Portland - American Legion Convention (1970 August-September )
  - Demonstrations - Vietnam War Protests (Box-folder 49/33)
    A majority of the photographs are of student demonstrations held in May 1970.
  - Department of Interior Building (Box-folder 49/34)
  - Dickinson Co. (Box-folder 49/35)
  - Dieringer's Woodstock Shopping Center (Box-folder 49/36)
  - Diesel Service Unit Co. (Box-folder 49/37)
  - Dimetre Electric Co. (Box-folder 49/38)
  - Disabled American Veterans Rehabilitation Center (Box-folder 49/39)
  - Disaster Drills (Box-folder 50/1)
  - Disaster Hoax, 1953 January 22 (Box-folder 50/2)
    Images related to incident wherein a man made calls claiming a major disaster, resulting in over 50 emergency vehicles rushing to Grant and Girls' Polytechnic High Schools.
  - Docks (Box-folder 50/3)
  - Dodge City (Box-folder 50/4)
  - Doernbecher Home (Box-folder 50/5)
    Residence of Frank Silas Doernbecher.
  - Doernbecher Manufacturing Co. (Box-folder 50/6)
  - Dolph Home (Box-folder 50/7)
    Residence of J. N. Dolph.
  - Don Neher Motors (Box-folder 50/8)
  - Dorman-Kanpe Gravel Pit (Box-folder 50/9)
  - Double-O Shop (Box-folder 50/10)
  - Downtown Athletic Club (Box-folder 50/11)
  - Downtown District (Box-folder 50/12)
  - Downtown Plaza (Box-folder 50/13)
  - Drop-In Center (Box-folder 50/14)
  - Drug Stores (Box-folder 50/15)
  - Dry Docks (Box-folder 50/16)
  - Dugan Cab Co. (Box-folder 50/17)
  - Duniway Center (Box-folder 50/18)
  - Duniway Park (Box-folder 50/19)
  - Duniway Plaza (Box-folder 50/20)
  - Dunne Home (Box-folder 50/21)
  - Dunthorpe Motor Transport (Box-folder 50/22)
  - Dwyer Lumber Co. (Box-folder 50/23)
  - Eagle Scouts (1) (Box-folder 50/24)
    See also: Portland - Boy Scouts.
  - Eagle Scouts (2) (Box-folder 50/25)
  - Eagles Lodge (Box-folder 50/26)
  - Earth Day Celebrations (Box-folder 50/27)
  - Eathquakes (Box-folder 50/28)
  - East Bank Esplenade (Box-folder 50/29)
  - "The East End" (Box-folder 50/30)
    Office complex in northeast Portland.
  - East-CAP (Box-folder 50/31)
  - East Gate Village (Box-folder 50/32)
  - East Multnomah Child Care Center (Box-folder 50/33)
  - East Portland Marina (Box-folder 50/34)
  - East Side Commercial Club (Box-folder 50/35)
  - East Side Railroad Terminal, 1884 (Box-folder 50/36)
  - Easter Celebrations (Box-folder 51/1)
  - Easter Seal Society (Box-folder 51/2)
  - Eastern Outfitting (Box-folder 51/3)
    Later became the Dierks Medical Building.
  - Eastmoreland District (Box-folder 51/4)
  - Eastmoreland Golf Course (Box-folder 51/5)
  - Eastport Plaza (Box-folder 51/6)
  - Edgewater Golf Club (Box-folder 51/7)
  - Educational Services Center (Box-folder 51/8)
  - Elections (Box-folder 51/9)
  - Electric Building (Box-folder 51/10)
  - Electric Contractors, Inc. (Box-folder 51/11)
  - Electric-Metallurgical Co. (Box-folder 51/12)
  - Electric Scientific Industries (Box-folder 51/13)
  - Elk Rock Island (Box-folder 51/14)
  - Elks Club (Box-folder 51/15)
  - Elks Temple (Box-folder 51/16)
  - Emperor Building (Box-folder 51/17)
    Contains image of building's demolition in 1968.
  - Emblem Club of Portland (Box-folder 51/18)
  - Epilepsy Leauge of Metropolitan Portland (Box-folder 51/19)
  - Epsilon Sigma Alpha (Box-folder 51/20)
  - Epworth League (Box-folder 51/21)
  - Equitable Savings & Loan Association (Box-folder 51/22)
  - Erickson's (Box-folder 51/23)
  - Errol Heights District (Box-folder 51/24)
  - Esco Corp. (Box-folder 51/25)
  - Evans Products Co. (Box-folder 51/26)
  - Ex-Newsboys Association (Box-folder 51/27)
  - Explosions (Box-folder 51/28)
    See also: Portland - Bombs and Bombings.
  - FMC Corp. (Box-folder 51/29)
  - Fabri-Valve Co. (Box-folder 51/30)
  - Factory Motor Car Co. (Box-folder 51/31)
  - Failing Building (Box-folder 52/1)
    Located at SW 5th and Alder.
  - Failing Home (Box-folder 52/2)
  - Fair Northwest, 1973 May (Box-folder 52/3)
  - Fairview Farms Little League Baseball Park (Box-folder 52/4)
  - Fairy Tale Parade (Box-folder 52/5)
  - Far West Federal Savings & Loan Association (Box-folder 52/6)
  - Farley Building (Box-folder 52/7)
  - Farmers Automobile Insurance (Box-folder 52/8)
  - Fashioncraft Furniture (Box-folder 52/9)
  - Father's Day Celebrations (Box-folder 52/10)
  - Feast of St. Francis Celebration, 1979 October 9 (Box-folder 52/11)
    Photographs of animals being blessed for the festival.
  - Federal Building (Box-folder 52/12)
    Includes 1963 photogtaphs of structures that previously stood on the site.
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) Office (Box-folder 52/13)
  - Federal Housing Administration (Box-folder 52/14)
  - Fields Motor Co. (Box-folder 52/15)
  - Fifty-Fifty Club (Box-folder 52/16)
  - Financial Center Building (Box-folder 52/17)
  - Fine Arts Building (Box-folder 52/18)
  - Finnish Summer Festival (Box-folder 52/19)
  - Fire Department (Box-folder 52/20)
    See also: Subjects - Firefighters and Firefighting.
  - Fires (1) (Box-folder 52/21)
  - Fires (2) (Box-folder 52/22)
  - Fires (3) (Box-folder 52/23)
  - Fires (4) (Box-folder 52/24)
  - Fires (5) (Box-folder 53/1)
  - Fires (6) (Box-folder 53/2)
  - Firestone Tire & Rubber Co. (Box-folder 53/3)
  - First Citizens (Box-folder 53/4)
  - First Family Home Buyers (Box-folder 53/5)
  - First Federal Savings & Loan Association (Box-folder 53/6)
  - First Flowers Insurance Building (Box-folder 53/7)
  - Fisher Body Craftsmen's Guild (Box-folder 53/8)
  - Fisk & Sunset Tire Corp. (Box-folder 53/9)
  - Flanders Professional Building (Box-folder 53/10)
  - Fleischner, Mayer & Co. (Box-folder 53/11)
  - Fletcher-Daniels Title Co. (Box-folder 53/12)
  - Floods (Box-folder 53/13)
  - Floods - May-June 1948 (Box-folder 53/14)
  - Floods - December 1964 (Box-folder 53/15)
  - Fluoridation Hearing, 1956 June 13 (Box-folder 53/16)
  - Folksinger's Coffee House (Box-folder 53/17)
  - Fong Trial, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 53/18)
    Photographs related to the trial of Wey Him ("Wayne") and Sherry Fong for the murder of Diane Hank; Wey Him was acquited, and Sherry convicted of second-degree murder.
  - Food Front (Box-folder 53/19)
  - Ford Motor Co. (Box-folder 53/20)
  - Ford Tractor Co. (Box-folder 53/21)
  - Forest Park (Box-folder 53/22)
  - Fouch Electric Manufacturing Co. (Box-folder 53/23)
  - Fountain Plaza Development (Box-folder 53/24)
  - Fountain Village Association (Box-folder 53/25)
  - Fountains (Box-folder 53/26)
    See also: Portland - David Campbell Memorial Fountain; Portland - Lovejoy Fountain Park.
  - Foursquare Church Youth Center (Box-folder 53/27)
  - Fowler Manufacturing Co. (Box-folder 53/28)
  - Frank Home (Box-folder 53/29)
    Residence of Sigmund Frank.
  - Franz Bakery (Box-folder 54/1)
  - Frazer Home (Box-folder 54/2)
  - Frazier & McLean Garage (Box-folder 54/3)
  - Frazier & McLean 's Livery Boarding & Sale Stable (Box-folder 54/4)
  - Fred Meyer, Inc. (Box-folder 54/5)
  - Freeman & Hayslip (Box-folder 54/6)
  - Freeman's Coffeehouse (Box-folder 54/7)
    Owned by Bernard Freeman.
  - Freightliner Corp. (Box-folder 54/8)
  - Friendly House (Box-folder 54/9)
  - Friendship Club (Box-folder 54/10)
  - Friendship House (Box-folder 54/11)
  - Frontier Ghost Town, 1959 (Box-folder 54/12)
    Recreation of old west ghost town set up in Park Blocks for the 1959 Portland Rose Festival.
  - Fruit & Flower Child Care Center (Box-folder 54/13)
    Also called Fruit & Flower Day Nursery and Fruit & Flower Mission.
  - G. I. Joe's (Box-folder 54/14)
  - Galleria (Box-folder 54/15)
  - Gamma Phi (Box-folder 54/16)
  - Garden Club (Box-folder 54/17)
  - Garden Home Child Care Center (Box-folder 54/18)
  - Garden Home Community Cannery (Box-folder 54/19)
  - Gates Rubber Co. (Box-folder 54/20)
  - General Electric (Box-folder 54/21)
  - General Mills (Box-folder 54/22)
  - General Motors Corp. (Box-folder 54/23)
  - General Motors Parade of Progress (Box-folder 54/24)
  - General Petroleum Building (Box-folder 54/25)
  - General Plant Corp. (Box-folder 54/26)
  - General Sales Co. (Box-folder 54/27)
  - General Telephone Co. (Box-folder 54/28)
  - General Tire & Rubber Co. (Box-folder 54/29)
  - George Home (Box-folder 54/30)
    Residence of Melvin J. George.
  - Georgia-Pacific Building (Box-folder 54/31)
  - Gerber Advertising Co. (Box-folder 54/32)
  - Gerber Legendary Blades (Box-folder 54/33)
  - Gillespie Decals, Inc. (Box-folder 55/1)
  - Gilmore Oil Co. (Box-folder 55/2)
  - Girl Scouts (Box-folder 55/3)
  - Gladding, McBean & Co. (Box-folder 55/4)
  - Glendoveer Golf Course (Box-folder 55/5)
  - Golden Age Club (Box-folder 55/6)
  - Good Friday Services (Box-folder 55/7)
  - Goodnaugh Buuilding (Box-folder 55/8)
  - Goodwill Industries (Box-folder 55/9)
  - Goodyear Tire & Rubber Co. (Box-folder 55/10)
  - Goose Hollow District (Box-folder 55/11)
  - Gordon's Stationery Co. (Box-folder 55/12)
  - Gourmet Gala, 1966 June (Box-folder 55/13)
  - Government Center Complex (Box-folder 55/14)
    Contains photograph of a model of the proposed 3-building complex.
  - Grand Army Cemetery (Box-folder 55/15)
  - Grand Army of the Republic Parade, 1931 June 23 (Box-folder 55/16)
  - Grand Central Market (Box-folder 55/17)
  - Grant & Roth Plastics (Box-folder 55/18)
  - Graphic Arts Building (Box-folder 55/19)
  - Gray Line Sightseeing Co. (Box-folder 55/20)
  - Gray Panthers (Box-folder 55/21)
  - Greater Portland Crusade, 1950 (Box-folder 55/22)
  - Greater Portland Industries Exposition, 1950 (Box-folder 55/23)
  - Greek Independence Day Celebrations (Box-folder 55/24)
  - Green Hills District (Box-folder 55/25)
  - Green Thumb Program (Box-folder 55/26)
  - Greenfingers Gardening Project (Box-folder 55/27)
  - Greyhound Bus Depot (Box-folder 55/28)
  - Guaranty Building (Box-folder 55/29)
  - Guardian Angels (Box-folder 55/30)
    Volunteer street-policing force.
  - Guild's Lake (Box-folder 55/31)
  - Gunderson Bros. Engineering Corp. (Box-folder 55/32)
  - Haack Laboratories (Box-folder 55/33)
  - Hadassah (Box-folder 55/34)
  - Halfway Houses (Box-folder 55/35)
  - Halloween Celebrations (1) (Box-folder 56/1)
    Includes haunted houses that operated during the Halloween season.
  - Halloween Celebrations (2) (Box-folder 56/2)
  - Halton Tractor Co. (Box-folder 56/3)
  - Hamilton Building (Box-folder 56/4)
  - Hanchett Manufacturing Co. (Box-folder 56/5)
  - Harbor (Box-folder 56/6)
  - Harbor Motor Co. (Box-folder 56/7)
  - Harbor Patrol (Box-folder 56/8)
  - Hare Krishna (Box-folder 56/9)
  - Harris Ice Machine Works (Box-folder 56/10)
  - Harris Office (Box-folder 56/11)
  - Harrison Square (Box-folder 56/12)
  - Harsh Building, 1953 March (Box-folder 56/13)
    Two images related to the dismantling of a barrier Joseph Ward erected on what he considered property boundary. Ward lost the disputed land in a court case.
  - Harsh-Ward Property Dispute (Box-folder 56/14)
  - Harvest Festival, 1980 November (Box-folder 56/15)
  - Hawthorne Electronics (Box-folder 56/16)
  - Hawthorne Park (Box-folder 56/17)
  - Hayden Island Yacht Club (Box-folder 56/18)
  - Hazeltine Building (Box-folder 56/19)
  - Heathman Garage (Box-folder 56/20)
  - Helm Building (Box-folder 56/21)
  - Hennigson Home (Box-folder 56/22)
  - Henry Building (Box-folder 56/23)
  - Henry Failing Building (Box-folder 56/24)
    Located on SW Oak Street.
  - Henry's (Box-folder 56/25)
    Restaurant opened by Henry Thiele
  - Hi-Fashion Fabrics (Box-folder 56/26)
  - Highland Games (1) (Box-folder 56/27)
  - Highland Games (2) (Box-folder 56/28)
  - Highlands Racquet Club (Box-folder 56/29)
  - Highlands Riding Academy (Box-folder 56/30)
    Also called Highlands School of Riding.
  - Hillsdale Camp (Box-folder 56/31)
  - Hillsdale Center (Box-folder 56/32)
  - Hillsdale Terrace (Box-folder 56/33)
  - Hirsch Home (Box-folder 57/1)
    Residence of Solomon Hirsch.
  - Hirsch-Weis Canvas Products Co. (Box-folder 57/2)
  - Holgate Shopping Center (Box-folder 57/3)
  - Holladay Bowl (Box-folder 57/4)
  - Holladay Center (Box-folder 57/5)
  - Hollywood Boosters (Box-folder 57/6)
  - Hollywood District (Box-folder 57/7)
    Includes a 1926 photograph of the Hollywood Theater.
  - Holy Name Rallies (Box-folder 57/8)
  - Holy Name Societies (Box-folder 57/9)
  - Holy Saturday Celebrations (Box-folder 57/10)
  - Home Loan Bank Board (Box-folder 57/11)
  - Home Planners Institute, 1946 January (Box-folder 57/12)
  - Home Social Club (Box-folder 57/13)
  - Honor Society (Box-folder 57/14)
  - Hoo Hoo Club (Box-folder 57/15)
  - Hop Growers Association Convention, 1949 July (Box-folder 57/16)
  - Horseless Carriage Club (Box-folder 57/17)
  - Hospitals and Clinics, Subseries 5
    - Bess Kaiser Hospital (Box-folder 57/18)
    - Child Guidance Clinic (Box-folder 57/19)
    - Children's Psychiatric Day Treatment Center (Box-folder 57/20)
    - Chiropractic Clinic & Health Center (Box-folder 57/21)
    - City of Roses Hospital (Box-folder 57/22)
    - Delaunay Institute for Mental Health (Box-folder 57/23)
    - Dental Arts Building (Box-folder 57/24)
    - Dierks Medical-Dental Building (Box-folder 57/25)
      Also called Portland Medical Center.
    - Doernbecher Children's Hospital (Box-folder 57/26)
    - Emanuel Hospital (Box-folder 57/27)
    - Flanders Medical Center (Box-folder 57/28)
    - Freedom House (Box-folder 57/29)
      A drug rehabilitation center.
    - Glisan St. Medical-Dental Building (Box-folder 57/30)
    - Good Samaritan Hospital (Box-folder 57/31)
    - Hahnemann Hospital (Box-folder 57/32)
    - Health Center for the Elderly (Box-folder 57/33)
    - Holladay Park Hospital (Box-folder 57/34)
    - Hooper Detoxification Center (Box-folder 57/35)
      Also called David Hooper Detoxification Center and Hooper Memorial Detoxification Center
    - House Calls, Inc. (Box-folder 57/36)
    - Isolation Hospital (Box-folder 57/37)
    - Kaiser Sunnyside Medical Center (Box-folder 57/38)
    - Medical Arts Building (Box-folder 58/1)
    - Medical Building, 25th and Lovejoy (Box-folder 58/2)
    - Medical-Dental Building (Box-folder 58/3)
    - Medical-Dental Clinics (Box-folder 58/4)
      Contains images of two buildings at NE Sandy and SE 76th dubbed "Medical-Dental Clinic"
    - Medical Center Hospital (Box-folder 58/5)
    - Moreland Children's Clinic (Box-folder 58/6)
    - Morningside Hospital (Box-folder 58/7)
    - Mulnomah County Hospital (Box-folder 58/8)
    - Oregon Health & Science University (OHSU) (Box-folder 58/9)
      Previously known as University of Oregon Medical School.
    - Physicians & Surgeons Hospital (Box-folder 58/10)
    - Portland Adventist Medical Center (Box-folder 58/11)
    - Portland General Hospital (Box-folder 58/12)
    - Portland Osteopathic Hospital (Box-folder 58/13)
    - Portland Sanitarium & Hospital (Box-folder 58/14)
    - Providence Hospital (Box-folder 58/15)
    - St. Vincent Hospital (Box-folder 58/16)
    - Shriner's Hospital (1) (Box-folder 58/17)
      Also called Shrine Hospital and Shriner's Hospital for Crippled Children.
    - Shriner's Hospital (2) (Box-folder 58/18)
    - University State Tuberculosis Hospital (Box-folder 58/19)
    - Verticare (Box-folder 58/20)
    - Veterans Administration Hospital (Box-folder 58/21)
    - Wemme Memorial Hospital (Box-folder 58/22)
    - Wilcox Memorial Hospital (Box-folder 58/23)
    - Woodland Park Hospital (Box-folder 58/24)
  - Hospital Week (Box-folder 58/25)
  - Hot Rod Club (Box-folder 58/26)
  - Hot Rod Council (Box-folder 58/27)
  - Hotels (1) (Box-folder 59/1)
  - Hotels (2) (Box-folder 59/2)
  - Hotels (3) (Box-folder 59/3)
  - Hotels (4) (Box-folder 59/4)
  - Hotels - "Today's Puzzle", 1976 (Box-folder 59/5)
    Series of photographs of building exteriors, fire escapes, etc. labeled "Hotel" paper-clipped with paper scrap labeled "Today's puzzle." Presumably readers were to guess which hotel was depicted in each picture.
  - House of Ideas (Box-folder 59/6)
  - Houseboat Moorage (Box-folder 59/7)
    Proposed housboat moorage on the Columbia River near the Portland International Airport that caused controversy.
  - Houses and Housing (1) (Box-folder 59/8)
  - Houses and Housing (2) (Box-folder 59/9)
  - Housing Authority of Portland (Box-folder 59/10)
  - Howard-Cooper Corp. (Box-folder 59/11)
  - Hoyt Arboretum (Box-folder 59/12)
  - Hughes Building (Box-folder 59/13)
  - Hunger Hikes (Box-folder 59/14)
  - Hunt Transfer Co. (Box-folder 59/15)
  - Hyster Co. (Box-folder 59/16)
  - Hyster Sales Co. (Box-folder 59/17)
  - Import Plaza (Box-folder 59/18)
  - Incinerators (Box-folder 59/19)
  - Independence Day Celebrations (Box-folder 59/20)
    Also known as Fourth of July celebrations.
  - Indian Center (Box-folder 59/21)
  - Indian Guides (Box-folder 59/22)
  - Industrial Air Products Co. (Box-folder 59/23)
  - Industrial Clinics (Box-folder 59/24)
  - Inman-Poulson Lumber Co. (Box-folder 60/1)
  - Interchurch Center (Box-folder 60/2)
  - Inter-City Buses, Inc. (Box-folder 60/3)
  - Interfaith Institute (Box-folder 60/4)
  - International Business Machines Co. (IBM) (Box-folder 60/5)
  - International Harvester Co. (Box-folder 60/6)
  - International Marketing Institute (Box-folder 60/7)
  - Interstate Commerce Commission Hearing, 1953 March (Box-folder 60/8)
  - Interstate Motor Lines (Box-folder 60/9)
  - Interurban Trains (Box-folder 60/10)
    See also: Portland - Streetcars; Subjects - Railroads.
  - Iris Court Day Care Center (Box-folder 60/11)
  - Iron Firemen Manufacturing Co. (Box-folder 60/12)
  - Irving Park (Box-folder 60/13)
  - Irvington Machine Works (Box-folder 60/14)
  - Irvington Tennis Club (Box-folder 60/15)
  - J. E. Haseltine Co. (Box-folder 60/16)
  - J. K. Gill Building (Box-folder 60/17)
  - J. P. Finley & Sons (Box-folder 60/18)
  - Jack-'N-Box Coffee Shop (Box-folder 60/19)
  - Jackson Home (Box-folder 60/20)
    Residence of C. S. ("Sam" Jackson"
  - Jackson Tower (Box-folder 60/21)
  - Jacobs Home (Box-folder 60/22)
    Residence of Ralph Jacobs.
    Contains photographs taken during building's demolition in 1940.
  - Janis Program (Box-folder 60/23)
  - Jantzen Beach (Box-folder 60/24)
  - Jantzen Knitting Mills (Box-folder 60/25)
  - Japanese Cemetery (Box-folder 60/26)
    Unidentified cemetery that is most likely in Portland.
  - Jarman-Williamson Co. (Box-folder 60/27)
  - Jefferson Substation (Box-folder 60/28)
  - Jennings Home (Box-folder 60/29)
  - Jewish Community Center (Box-folder 60/30)
  - Jewish Holiday Celebrations (Box-folder 60/31)
  - Jewish National Fund (Box-folder 60/32)
  - Jewish Welfare Fund (Box-folder 60/33)
  - Jo-Paul Industries (Box-folder 60/34)
  - Job's Daughters (Box-folder 60/35)
  - Joe Weiner's (Box-folder 61/1)
  - John Deere Plow Building (Box-folder 61/2)
  - John F. Kennedy Library Exhibit, 1964 October (Box-folder 61/3)
  - Johns Landing (Box-folder 61/4)
  - Johnson Home Model (Box-folder 61/5)
    Small reconstruction of the residence of William Johnson's house, the first in Portland.
  - Junior Chamber of Commerce (Box-folder 61/6)
  - Junior Chamber of Commerce Convention, 1971 June (Box-folder 61/7)
  - Junior Traffic Club (Box-folder 61/8)
  - Justice Center (Box-folder 61/9)
  - Juvenile Detention Home (Box-folder 61/10)
  - Kamm Building (Box-folder 61/11)
  - Kamm Home (Box-folder 61/12)
    Residence of Jacob Kamm.
  - Kappa Alpha Theta (Box-folder 61/13)
  - "Kazoo-In", 1968 January 22 (Box-folder 61/14)
  - Kelly Home (Box-folder 61/15)
    Residence of Clinton Kelly.
  - Kelly Point Park (Box-folder 61/16)
  - Kendall Community Center (Box-folder 61/17)
  - Kenton District (Box-folder 61/18)
  - (Daniel) Kerr Home (Box-folder 61/19)
    Residence of Daniel Kerr.
  - (Peter) Kerr Home (Box-folder 61/20)
    Residence of Peter Kerr.
  - Killingsworth Home (Box-folder 61/21)
  - Killon Home (Box-folder 61/22)
  - King Home (Box-folder 61/23)
  - Kinney Shoe Stores (Box-folder 61/24)
  - Kirkman Laboratories (Box-folder 61/25)
  - Kiwanis International Convention, 1946 July (Box-folder 61/26)
  - Knapp Home (Box-folder 61/27)
    Residence of Richard B. Knapp
  - Knights of Columbus (Box-folder 61/28)
  - Knights of Columbus Convention, 1949 August (Box-folder 61/29)
  - Knights Templar (Box-folder 61/30)
  - Knott Street Community Center (Box-folder 61/31)
  - Knott Street Swimming Pool (Box-folder 61/32)
  - Kraft Foods Co. (Box-folder 61/33)
  - Kwong Mow Hand Laundry (Box-folder 61/34)
  - La Grand Industrial Supply (Box-folder 61/35)
  - La Leche League (Box-folder 61/36)
  - Labadie Home (Box-folder 61/37)
    Residence of Joseph J. Labadie
  - Labor Temple (Box-folder 61/38)
  - Laco Village (Box-folder 61/39)
  - Ladd Circle (Box-folder 62/1)
  - Lamb-Weston, Inc. (Box-folder 62/2)
  - Lambert Gardens (Box-folder 62/3)
  - Lambert Home (Box-folder 62/4)
  - Landslides (Box-folder 62/5)
  - Last Man Club (Box-folder 62/6)
  - Latch Key Programs (Box-folder 62/7)
  - Laubach Literacy, Inc. (Box-folder 62/8)
  - Laurelhurst Club (Box-folder 62/9)
  - Laurelhurst Park (Box-folder 62/10)
  - Laurence Warehouse Co. (Box-folder 62/11)
  - Law Day Celebrations (Box-folder 62/12)
  - Lazarus Building (Box-folder 62/13)
  - Leach Botanical Gardens (Box-folder 62/14)
  - Leadbetter Home (Box-folder 62/15)
  - League of Women Voters (Box-folder 62/16)
  - "Learn-to-Swim" Campaign (Box-folder 62/17)